ana enders



www.anaenders.com ana.enders@gmail.com www.github.com/anaenders

profile

Hello. I am a website developer and designer. I've spent the past few years implementing web compliant sites using HTML, HAML, CSS, SASS, and JavaScript through JQuery and CoffeeScript. Due to my basic understanding of Object Oriented Programming and my personal interest in programming languages, such as Java, Ruby and Python, I feel comfortable manipulating code written by software engineers. All the while, I am a designer and creative at heart, which I express primarily through Photoshop. My design intuition and experience as a developer have made me particularly qualified to do site-wide QA testing on various platforms and operating systems. In short, I am the pixel-perfect attention-to-detail glue between the design and backend engineering teams using my skills to facilitate and contribute to both worlds.

education

Senior Designer and Front-end Engineer - *The Muse*

New York, NY - July 2012 - Present

As the Senior Designer and Front-end Engineer, I deliver HTML, SASS, and JavaScript via JQuery and CoffeeScript for our Python & Tornado based app. I also provide designs from concept to implementation.

experience

.

2001 - 2005 | Carnegie Mellon University BFA Music Performance, European Studies

2007 - 2008 | Parsons School of Design

MFA Design + Technology

likes

Freelance Front-end Developer - <u>Self Employed</u>

San Francisco, CA - July 2012 - 09/2011 - 07/2012 (9 months)

Freelancing for old clients in need of front-end adjustments to their existing sites. Also worked on some logo and branding designs.

Clients: Tiffany & co. | Juice Generation | NewlyWish | Hackbright Academy

Interior design

· Bea Arthur ice cream cone from Big Gay's

· Home-made waffles

 Cuddles from my cat & dog while binge watching TV shows with Ian

Front-end Developer - <u>Intersect NYC (a.k.a. Crown Partners a.k.a. Razorfish)</u>

New York, NY - 09/2008 - 09/2011 (3 years 1 month)

As a member of the development team, I worked closely with the designers, backend programmers, and software engineers in producing custom e-commerse sites and content management software.

Clients: Kenneth Cole | Liz Claiborne | Boast USA | Carlos Falchi | Chilewich | Thornton Tomasetti | Yigal Azrouël

dislikes

• IPAs

· Winter and Summer

· Waking up early

skills

